Pierre Nguyen

425-246-9459 | | pierrepnguyen@gmail.com | | http://pierrepnguyen.com https://linkedin.com/in/pierrepnguyen/ | | http://github.com/pierrepnguyen

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Developer with more to offer than coding alone. Professional technical expertise in full-stack web development, application development, algorithms, object-oriented programming and UX/UI design. Demonstrated expertise in quickly picking up new technologies and concepts. Over 5 years of experience in fast paced & customer service-oriented environment. Fluent in French and Vietnamese.

EDUCATION

Coding Dojo, Bellevue, WA

January 2019 - April 2019

Full-Stack Web Development – Stacks: Web Fundamentals, Python, C#, MEAN

WORK HISTORY

SoftwareONE, Remote/Renton, WA

April 2021 - September 2021

Associate Software Engineer

Collaborate with developers in a way that is consistent with agile development practices. Finalized & tested batch job flows in Power Automate to set up weekly alerts. Created innovative interaction designs through explorations, user flows, and wireframes. Developed a front-end for the SAP telemetry team to manage business operations.

Microsoft, Sammamish, WA

September 2020 – April 2021

Software Engineer

Collaborate with developers in a way that is consistent with agile development practices. Finalized & tested batch job flows in Power Automate to set up weekly alerts. Created innovative interaction designs through explorations, user flows, and wireframes using Figma. Developed a front-end for the SAP telemetry team to manage business operations with React.

Technical Skills

Languages: C#, Python, Java, JavaScript (ES5, ES6), TypeScript, HTML5, CSS

Front-end/Libraries: Mongoose, React, jQuery, Ajax, Bootstrap, Materialize, SocketIO **Frameworks:** Angular5, Flask, Django, Node, Express, ASP.NET, Entity, Microsoft Bot **Dev Tools:** AWS EC2, GitHub, VS Code, Postman, MySQL Workbench & XCode 10

Methodologies: MVC, OOP, CRUD Operations, RESTful Architecture

Database: MongoDB, MySQL, SQLite, Kusto

PROJECTS

Karen (Technologies used: Python, Django, SQLite, JavaScript, HTML, CSS)

Created an artificial intelligent application to search anything on the internet, send emails and make events on the calendar.

Restaurant Suggestion Bot (Technologies used: Microsoft Bot Framework, Python, API)

Created a chat bot using the Microsoft Bot Framework to give restaurant suggestions with an adaptive card. The card will display a review out of 5 ★ and a link to their restaurant website.

Drunk Card Game (Technologies used: C#, Entity, MySQL, HTML, CSS)

Created a virtual version of a drinking card game. This app allows users to let off some steam and enjoy oneself on the weekend.